

Francisco Almeida

BSc Finalist Student



March 15 1996



Sintra, Lisbon



+351 965 642 261

franciscopalmeida.github.io/resume



frpv.almeida@gmail.com

About me ——

I'm a 24 year old student and aspiring frontend / fullstack developer, living in Sintra, Portugal.

Currently in the last semester of my Computer Engineering Bachelor's degree at Instituto Superior Técnico. I greatly enjoy working in team environments as they provide a fantastic growth and learning opportunity, both in terms of personal and professional development.

Python C Java MySQL Javascript HTML NodeJS ReactJs

Interests)

Programming has always been a passion of mine due to how similar it feels to puzzle solving and I always strive to find the most efficient solution to a problem.

I have a strong interest in physical activities, having played tennis for over five years and practiced swimming for over four years, and recently focused on maintaining a healthy lifestyle.

Education

since 2014 BSc. in Computer Engineering

Instituto Superior Técnico

2011-2014 High school

Escola Secundária de Santa Maria

Relevant Subjects

Computer Networks

Concluded with an average of 15/20

Computer Graphics

Concluded with an average of 15/20

Machine-Person Interfaces

Concluded with an average of 14/20

Experience

Summer Internship at EDUdigital July 2020 - September 2020 Fullstack solo development of a Recruitment application, utilizing ReactJs (particularly NextJs) and Material-UI for the frontend and NodeJs (particularly ExpressJs) together with MySQL for the backend .

Transcriptions and Translations

November 2019 - April 2020

Performed dozens of Portuguese-English (and vice-versa) translations / transcriptions at GoTranscript with my lowest evaluation ever being a 92%

Retail

I have worked in retail in several occasions, which has contributed to the general improvement of my soft skills, adaptability and reaction to unknown scenarios, as well as being involved in a teamwork environment.

Programming Languages and technologies

I have experience coding in C, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL/PostgreSQL, and Bash in college, and have utilized NodeJs, ReactJs and various frameworks in the previously mentioned internship. I have also built an online resume with ReactJS, utilizing Material-UI and CSS3.

Link: franciscopalmeida.github.io/resume

Relevant information

Languages:

English: C1 (Advanced)
Portuguese: Natural
Spanish: B1 (Intermediate)